tiqets.com 2019-05-01

# Privacy Policy

## Introduction

This privacy policy describes the way our company, Tiqets International B.V. and our group companies, collect, store, process and use personal data. As a visitor or customer of the www.tiqets.com website, Tiqets iOS and Android applications and other applications that facilitate our products and services, you have given your consent for our collection and use of your personal data. We use this data to improve our products and services and help you discover and embrace cultural experiences. As personal data can be directly or indirectly linked to your identity, contact information or location, we take our responsibility to safeguarding your personal data very seriously.

Please read this privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use and protect your personal data. We may amend this privacy policy from time to time and, if you have any questions, remarks or requests relating to this privacy policy, please reach out to us by using the contact details below.

## Personal data

Your name, telephone number, email address and data relating to your activities on our website are examples of information that directly or indirectly relates to your identity, contact information or location.

We also collect your personal data when you visit our website or use one of our mobile applications. This information may include your IP address, location details, general preferences, settings and system specifications.

The most evident way we gather personal data is when you place an order, subscribe to our newsletter, set up an account, communicate with our customer service or when you leave a comment, review or other information on our website or mobile applications. In addition, you may be asked to grant access to your current location when using the website or mobile applications, which is done to identify and help you discover cultural experiences and attractions in your area. Finally, if you reached Tiqets through a third party (such as another website or reseller), we may also receive your personal data from them.

## How we use personal data

We use your personal data for a number of reasons, in particular:

  * _To ensure overall smooth operations_ – your personal data helps us to constantly improve our website and mobile applications and enables us to quickly process your transactions.
  * _Tailoring content_ – by personalising our website and mobile applications' content, we can provide you with relevant products and services suited to your interests and needs.
  * _Reviews_ – we collect personal data provided in your reviews, for example, by registering the venue you visited and analyze this feedback to evaluate a particular product or service. We also use platforms such as Facebook and Trustpilot for reviews. Please read our Terms and Conditions for more information regarding reviews and feedback.
  * _Customer assistance_ – in order to streamline your communications with our customer service agents, we use personal data, such as your telephone number to: 
    * Quickly and securely establish your identity and link directly to your order history
    * Facilitate follow-ups via phone, email or live chats. When we believe you may need our assistance i.e. if you cancel a transaction during the final stage of the booking process. We then use your personal data to ask if you require assistance.
    * Finally, we may get in contact to update you on any exceptional circumstances that are beyond our control by may affect your experience with our products or services, including but not limited to general strikes and threats to your personal safety.
  * _Marketing purposes_ – this boils down to semi-personalized communications including newsletters (see more information below) and promotions of our products and services on other websites you may visit, including social media websites.
  * _Overall legal compliance_ – your personal data also plays a key role in helping us identify and prevent fraudulent transactions or other illegal activities on our platform, communicate security messages to our customers and comply with relevant applicable laws and regulations.
  * _Safe payments_ – we work together with payment service partners, such as Adyen, on all payment transactions. We don't have access to your full payment details, but we may refer to partial information, such as the last couple of digits of your credit card number, for authentication and anti-fraud purposes.

We will only store your personal data temporarily for the purposes listed above, save for situations where laws or regulations dictate otherwise.

## Newsletters

We use newsletters to inform you on recent developments and introduce our new products, special offers and promotions. You can unsubscribe from these newsletters at any time by clicking the ‘Unsubscribe' link in the newsletter or, alternatively, by contacting us through our contact details stated at the bottom of this privacy policy. Although we appreciate any feedback you may have, you don't need to provide a reason for unsubscribing from our newsletter.

## Your user accounts

You may have created a Tiqets account by verifying your email address, connecting through Facebook, Google or by other means. By signing up for an account through third party services (e.g. Facebook or Google), you grant us the right to confirm your identity with these services and access your personal details as explained under ‘Personal data' above.

## Location

You will always be asked to give permission before we can access your location from any mobile devices you may be using. By sharing your location, we can provide you with an overview of interesting cultural experiences in the area and help you locate the desired venue. You can withdraw your consent at any time by changing your computer or mobile device's privacy settings.

## Legal bases

We are registered as a company under Dutch law, which specifies a number of legal bases that justify the use of personal data. Our use of your personal data is based on three legal bases:

  * _Performance of a contract_ – we might use your data based on a contract you may have with us. We may then use said data to, for instance, process online purchases for one or several of our products or services.
  * _Legitimate interest_ – based on a case of legitimate interest, which includes economic interests, we may use your personal data to, for example, tailor our content to best fit your preferences, or to fulfil our legal obligation as a company under Dutch law to ensure proper administration practices.
  * _Consent_ – based on your explicit consent, we may use your personal data for any reasons detailed in the consent agreement e.g. to send you regular newsletters. You always have the choice to withdraw your consent - just let us know by contacting us through the contact details at the bottom of this privacy policy.

## Cookies and Google Analytics

We want you to enjoy visiting our platform, and we use cookies to ensure that our website (www.tiqets.com) runs smoothly and reliably. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. These cookies are placed on your device by your web browser and are either removed each time you close your browser or stored for a longer period of time. Cookies that aren't removed are sent back to us by your web browser the next time you visit. This enables us to recognize your computer or mobile device and improve and personalize your interactions and experiences on the Tiqets website. We also use other tracking technologies that are similar to cookies, such as third party tools, to achieve the same goal.

We strive to not embed cookies with a lifespan longer than one year, although there may be exceptions to this time period. Cookies can be placed on your devices by us or by a third party, such as Google Analytics (Google's official web analytics service). Google Analytics allows us to understand, in aggregate fashion, where visitors land on our website and how they use the site. We cannot disaggregate this data to analyze your individual behavior on our website.

Our website uses technical, functional, analytical and commercial cookies.

  * _Technical cookies_ – these are necessary to provide the requested service. For instance, technical cookies allow you to proceed through different pages of a website with a single login.
  * _Functional cookies_ – these cookies help our website and mobile applications "remember" your preferences i.e. language selection, search history and registration information.
  * _Analytics cookies_ – these cookies are placed by third party service providers, such as Google Analytics, and track how you find and interact with our website or mobile applications. This tracking system can be quite detailed, examining the average amount of mouse movements, scrolling activities, search words used and text entered in various fields. We can use this information to make our website easier to find, improve your interaction with our platform or measure the impact of our online marketing efforts. We want to point out that these third party service providers may also use information gathered about you on other websites or mobile applications over which we have no control. If you want to know more about how Google Analytics collects, uses and protects your privacy, you can consult Google's privacy policy by visiting [www.google.com/policies/privacy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).
  * _Commercial cookies_ – these cookies are used for tailoring our newsletters to your preferences and personalizing online advertisements. Such personalized adverts can also be shown on other websites you visit. This "retargeting" is based on your browsing activities, such as cultural attractions you're searching for. Commercial cookies can also help prevent the same advertisement continuously reappearing on different sites.

The consent you give us to store and use our and third party cookies can be withdrawn at any time by setting your browser to disable cookies and/or remove all cookies from your browser. However, please take into account that this may limit your access to certain functions and areas on our platform. Alternatively, if you do not wish to receive tailored advertising, visit [www.networkadvertising.org](https://www.networkadvertising.org/) to opt out of most companies that engage in such advertising.

## Third party access to personal data

We work with a number of third parties and may share your personal data for certain purposes.

  * _Suppliers_ – we may share your personal data with selected ticket suppliers. This information is used to complete, confirm or personalize your booking and can include your name, email address and telephone number.
  * _Other Tiqets entities_ – we may share your information with our legal subsidiaries and other Tiqets entities that are part of the Tiqets corporate family.
  * _Business partners_ – if you book an admission ticket with us through one of our business partners, it's possible that such business partner receives your personal data, which they can then use for their own purposes. In this context, your information is governed by the privacy policies of these business partners. We may also share personal data with our partners to prevent or identify fraudulent transactions or other illegal activities on our platform (for which we rely on the legal basis of performance of a task of public interest).
  * _Other third parties_ – we use the services of third parties that collect, monitor and analyse personal data on our behalf, including Google. Such third parties are also used to personalize and distribute marketing materials, including advertisements. We also use third parties to process your payments, sharing your personal data with them in order to complete financial transactions. All these parties are under the obligation to keep your personal data confidential, and can only use it for the initial purposes set out by Tiqets. 

For example:  
In order for you to select an interesting voucher offer, we may transmit your IP address and data related to your order to Sovendus GmbH. The IP address is processed by Sovendus in encrypted form, will be exclusively used for data security purposes, and will be anonymised seven days after receipt. The order data will be used by Sovendus for billing purposes. For more information on the processing of your data, visit [www.sovendus.co.uk/privacy_policy](https://www.sovendus.co.uk/privacy_policy).

  * _Legal obligations_ – we may have to disclose your personal data to the extent that we are required to do so by applicable laws and regulations.

## How we protect personal data

We are committed to safeguarding your personal data against unauthorised usage, modification, publication or deletion of said data. To achieve a high level of protection, we take a variety of both physical and technical security measures. Physical security measures include restricted and monitored access to our offices and user protection measures on laptops and computers. Our technical measure include regular website and mobile application scans to identify security gaps and vulnerabilities. We also use malware scanning, and your personal data is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons with special access rights to such systems. These individuals are specifically required to keep your personal data confidential. All sensitive information you provide is also encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. Finally, we do not store or have access to your full credit card details. Instead, we rely on our PCI-compliant payment service partner Adyen to safely store and process this information.

## Access to your personal data

You have the right to receive information about your personal data in a clear and accessible way. In addition, if your personal data contains incorrect information, or if you consider this information is used, stored or processed incorrectly, we are happy to correct, complete or remove such data as soon as possible. The deletion of your user account is also possible at any time. Please contact us through the email address provided at the bottom of this privacy policy. To help us respond to such requests in a prompt manner, please include "Personal Data request" in the subject line of your email.

## This privacy policy

We reserve the right to implement changes to this privacy policy. We will always publish the new version of this privacy policy on our website and will include the date of the latest version. As we will not proactively inform you regarding all changes made by us, we recommend you revisit this privacy policy from time to time. If you continue using our platform after we've made new amendments, we assume you acknowledge and agree with its latest content.

## Who controls your personal data?

Tiqets International B.V. controls your personal data on its website, mobile applications and other applications that facilitate our products and services. Tiqets International B.V. is a Dutch limited liability company, incorporated under the laws of the Netherlands and registered with the Amsterdam Chamber of Commerce (no. 59620285). Tiqets International B.V.'s address is James Wattstraat 100-4, 1097 DM Amsterdam, the Netherlands.

If you have any comments, requests, questions or otherwise would like to contact us about this privacy policy, please contact our customer service through [customerservice@tiqets.com](mailto:customerservice@tiqets.com).

6 December 2017
